import { Exercise } from ".";

export const SPORT: Exercise[] = [
  {
    "question": "футбол",
    "answer": "futboł",
    "extra": "⚽"
  },
  {
    "question": "баскетбол",
    "answer": "basketboł",
    "extra": "🏀"
  },
  {
    "question": "теннис",
    "answer": "tiennis",
    "extra": "🎾"
  },
  {
    "question": "волейбол",
    "answer": "wołejboł",
    "extra": "🏐"
  },
  {
    "question": "гольф",
    "answer": "gołf",
    "extra": "⛳"
  },
  {
    "question": "хоккей",
    "answer": "hokkiey",
    "extra": "🏒"
  },
  {
    "question": "бокс",
    "answer": "boks",
    "extra": "🥊"
  },
  {
    "question": "плавание",
    "answer": "pławanie",
    "extra": "🏊"
  },
  {
    "question": "бег",
    "answer": "bieg",
    "extra": "🏃"
  },
  {
    "question": "йога",
    "answer": "joga",
    "extra": "🧘"
  },
  {
    "question": "лыжи",
    "answer": "łyży",
    "extra": "🎿"
  },
  {
    "question": "сноубординг",
    "answer": "snoubording",
    "extra": "🏂"
  },
  {
    "question": "конькобежный спорт",
    "answer": "kon´kobieżnyj sport",
    "extra": "⛸️"
  },
  {
    "question": "велоспорт",
    "answer": "wielosport",
    "extra": "🚴"
  },
  {
    "question": "фехтование",
    "answer": "fiechtowanie",
    "extra": "🤺"
  },
  {
    "question": "каратэ",
    "answer": "karatie",
    "extra": "🥋"
  },
  {
    "question": "гимнастика",
    "answer": "gimnastika",
    "extra": "🤸"
  },
  {
    "question": "регби",
    "answer": "riegbi",
    "extra": "🏉"
  },
  {
    "question": "серфинг",
    "answer": "sierfing",
    "extra": "🏄"
  },
  {
    "question": "скейтбординг",
    "answer": "skejtbording",
    "extra": "🛹"
  },
  {
    "question": "альпинизм",
    "answer": "ałpinizm",
    "extra": "🧗"
  },
  {
    "question": "стрельба из лука",
    "answer": "striel´ba iz łuka",
    "extra": "🏹"
  },
  {
    "question": "шахматы",
    "answer": "szachmaty",
    "extra": "♟️"
  },
  {
    "question": "бильярд",
    "answer": "bil´jard",
    "extra": "🎱"
  },
  {
    "question": "каятинг",
    "answer": "kajat´ing",
    "extra": "🚣"
  },
  {
    "question": "парусный спорт",
    "answer": "parusnyj sport",
    "extra": "⛵"
  },
  {
    "question": "подводное плавание",
    "answer": "podwodnoje pławanije",
    "extra": "🤿"
  },
  {
    "question": "крикет",
    "answer": "krikiet",
    "extra": "🏏"
  },
  {
    "question": "американский футбол",
    "answer": "amierikanskij futboł",
    "extra": "🏈"
  }
];
